Guide to the Auxiliary Services Reference Collection, 1912-ongoing
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Auxiliary Services Reference collection 1912-ongoing
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. University Archives
1.0 Linear Feet 1000 Items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Auxiliary Services Reference Collection was compiled from various sources by University Archives staff for reference and research.
Historical Note
In an effort to bring all the revenue producing branches of the Business and Finance Division under one office in the early 1960s a Business Auxiliaries department was organized. It included Administrative Data Processing, Dining Halls, Housing Management and University Stores, and later, the Computation Center. From 1976 to 1980 a Campus Services department oversaw a number of activities that had been previously administered by the Physical Plant Department. These included custodial services, grounds maintenance, studio productions, office equipment, transportation, and mail. In 1980 the Auxiliary Services Division was created to replace Business Auxiliaries and Campus Services. In 2009, it was responsible for the operations of food services, special events and conference services, transportation and parking, housekeeping, housing management, office services, and the campus stores. See the newsletter, News and Views, FY1994-1995, for a history. In earlier years, parking was managed by Public Safety (now the Duke Police Dept.), but materials from that period are housed in this collection, rather than under Public Safety.
Collection Overview
The Auxiliary Services Reference Collection contains reports, memoranda, publications, schedules, flyers, charts, news clippings and other materials about the operations of Auxiliary Services. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
CD-ROMs.
Duke University. Auxiliary Services.
Duke University. University Archives.
Related Material
Business and Finance Division Records, 1956-1983.
University Archives, Duke University.
Media Services (Duke Studios) Audio and Video Recordings, 1963-2005.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Administration, 1976- (Box 1)
  - Annual Report, 1999-2000
  - The Blue Line [newsletter], 1992
  - Guide - Duke University Services, 1986; 1988
  - Management Services Department, 1970-1971
  - So - You're There: Resources for First-Year Duke Students, 1998, 2000 (CD-ROM)
  - The Year in Review - Duke University Auxiliary Services, 2001-2002
  - Duke Barber / Beauty Shop, 1912-
  - Duke Card, 1986-
  - Duke Postal Operations, 1970-
  - Duke University Stores. Bookstore, 1961-1986, undated
  - Duke University Stores. Calendars, 1980/81, 1990/91, 1992/93
  - Duke University Stores. Catalogs, 1978-2000, undated (3 folders)
  - Duke University Stores. Clippings and history, 1920-
  - Duke University Stores. Computer Store
  - Duke University Stores. Copying and printing, 1970- (3 folders)
  - Duke University Stores. Flyers, brochures, etc. 1962-
  - Duke University Stores. Gothic Bookshop - Catalogs, 1958-
  - Duke University Stores. Gothic Bookshop - Clippings, 1982-
  - Duke University Stores. Gothic Bookshop - Flyers and memoranda, 1960-
  - Duke University Stores. Laundry
  - Duke University Stores. Reports - "Games Program" [i.e., video games], 1981 (Box 2)
  - Duke University Stores. Reports - "Zero Base Budget…, 1982/83"
  - Duke University Stores. Reports - "Convenience Store, 1982"
  - Media Services, 1973-1983
  - Student Labor Pool, 1978-1988
  - Transportation and Parking. Accidents, 1992 - Amy Geissinger
  - Transportation and Parking. Bus schedules, 1935-1998, undated
  - Transportation and Parking. BRH Mobility Services transit planning proposal, 1973
  - Transportation and Parking. Clippings, 1977-
  - Transportation and Parking. Memoranda and notices, 1969-
  - Transportation and Parking. Maps and regulations, 1971-1982
  - Transportation and Parking. Regulation booklets, 1970-1983